Amol Sitaram Gawali 🕡 Featured

Application Development Experience in Apache Spark, Apache Kafka and Core JAVA. Search engine development experience in Apache Solr.



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 11 Month(s)

Current Company: L&T Infotech Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, Core Java, Apache Solr

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 16-Jan-21 Last Modified: 16-Jan-21

Summary

2 years of experience in Spark Streaming Application Development. A regular contributor to system enhancement. Hands on Spark Tuning and Application Design for better resources utilization in a cluster. Part of Spark SQL and Spark ML development. 1 year experience in Apache Solr.

Work Experience

L&T Infotech as Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2020 to Till Date

Working as senior software engineer on Apache Solr and Core Java

Gridlogics Technologies as Software Engineer

Jan 2019 to Jul 2020

Worked as software developer on Apache Solr and Core Java.

Network Components Pvt Ltd, as Junior Software Engineer

Aug 2016 to Aug 2018

1. Junior Software Engineer at Network Components Pvt Ltd, Pune Aug-2016 to Sep 2018

Project: Clouzer.com -A SaaS based Product for managing personal data and schedule on cloud.

Technology:

Frontend: HTML5, JavaScript, AngularJS, IndexedDb, Localstoarage

Backend: Node.js, Core Java, Socket.io, Apache Hbase, Hapi.js, Redis, Apache Ignite, Apache Kafka, Apache Spark.

Team size : 16 Responsibilities:

Write Spark flows for application requirement using spark streaming and spark structured streaming.

Spark Cluster Tuning for efficeient processing.

Spark SQL for data PreProcessing.

Case Study on Spark ML for future use in application.

Actively involved in deciding spark flows for better parallel computing using spark cluster.

Implemented DAG concept across various spark application for better design of application request processing.

Imlemented spark flows for better resource utilization with help of Apache Kafka and Apache Spark.

Project: ?IOT? based Web Application for managing data of electronic devices.

Technology:

Frontend: HTML5, JavaScript, AngularJS

Backend: Node.js, Core Java, Socket.io, Apache Hbase, Apache Ignite

Team size : 5 Responsibilities:

Worked for building a IOT(Internet of Things) based web application for electronic devices.

Actively involved in deciding flow of Application.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Pune University in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
CORE JAVA		2018	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Apache Kafka		2018	6 Month(s)	
Apache Spark		2018	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Apache Solr			1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			
Marathi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Search Engine For Patent Search (Patentinsightpro)

Client: -

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Project Location: Pune

Role: Sr. Programmer

Duration: Jan 2019 - Jul 2019
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 4

Skill Used: Apache Solr, Core Java

Role Description: Working on client issues, Semantic Search, Server monitoring, Solr code modifications as per requirement.

Project Details: Search Engine For Patent Search

Project Title: A SaaS based Product for managing personal data and schedule on cloud

Client: -

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2016 - Nov 2018

Role: Other Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 16

Skill Used: Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, Core Java Role Description: Spark Streaming Application Developer

Project Details: Technology Used in Project:

Frontend: HTML5, JavaScript, AngularJS, IndexedDb, Localstoarage

Backend: Node.js, Core Java, Socket.io, Apache Hbase, Hapi.js, Redis, Apache Ignite, Apache Kafka, Apache Spark.

Project Title: IOT based Web Application for managing data of electronic devices.

Client: -

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=03c2dd565dc383d0267da201144ae8eb0e0801024b1b0b16041844505...

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Aug 2016 - Nov 2018 Role: Other Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, Core Java Role Description: Spark Streaming Application Developer

Project Details: Technology:

Frontend: HTML5, JavaScript, AngularJS

Backend: Node.js, Core Java, Socket.io, Apache Hbase, Apache Ignite

Affirmative Action

Category: OBC - non-creamy Countries: India

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization